<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Aziz&#39;s Portfolio | Amirul Abdul Aziz</title>
    <link>//azizamir.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Aziz&#39;s Portfolio | Amirul Abdul Aziz</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//azizamir.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>//azizamir.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//azizamir.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello, I’m Amirul Abdul Aziz, a petroleum geoscientist with a strong focus on reservoir modeling, integrated formation evaluation, and quantitative interpretation.
Currently, I&amp;rsquo;m working as a Jr. Exploration Geoscientist at Proteknik Utama, focusing on basin-to-prospect-scale G&amp;amp;G studies. I&amp;rsquo;ve also worked at Kangean Energy Indonesia, Reckitt, Ula, Kargo Technologies, and Pure Earth Indonesia.
I hold a Bachelor of Engineering in Geophysical Engineering from Universitas Brawijaya. My undergraduate thesis titled “Petrophysical Modeling and Analysis for Reservoir Potential Assessment and Drilling Zone Prediction in the Kittiwake Field, North Sea, United Kingdom” focused on petrophysical analysis and reservoir modeling of the Kittiwake Field, North Sea, United Kingdom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qualitative Seismic Interpretation</title>
      <link>//azizamir.github.io/projects-learning/project-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//azizamir.github.io/projects-learning/project-01/</guid>
      <description>This is part of my learning routines where I enrolled in practical qualitative seismic interpretation courses in February 2024. I gained new knowledge on how to utilize Petrel features &amp;amp; perform effective seismic interpretation in Petrel.
Figure 1. Types of seismic data and bit
Figure 2. Petrel troubleshooting &amp;amp; features
Figure 3. Seismic data preparation for seismic interpretation (opacity &amp;amp; bump maping)
Figure 4. Structural attribute to enchance interpretation process</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantitative Seismic Interpretation</title>
      <link>//azizamir.github.io/projects-learning/project-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//azizamir.github.io/projects-learning/project-02/</guid>
      <description>In November 2024, I learn quantitative seismic interpretation through a public lecture course where I gained new knowledge on the theory of seismic QI, rock physics, and its implementation. This course taught me how to perform various seismic QI implementations, such as AVO modeling, pre-stack seismic inversion, and post-stack seismic inversion using demo data with Hampson-Russell software.
Figure 1. AVO modeling
Figure 2. Pre-stack seismic inversion
Figure 3. Post-stack seismic inversion</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Static Reservoir Modeling</title>
      <link>//azizamir.github.io/projects-learning/project-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//azizamir.github.io/projects-learning/project-03/</guid>
      <description>As part of my learning routines, I’m reviewing my knowledge on reservoir modeling, particularly on static reservoir modeling workflow through a public course from March to October 2024. The course using the Gulfaks field, an oil &amp;amp; gas field located in the Norwegian part of the North Sea shelf that operated by Statoil since 1986, as the demo data. Throughout this course, I learn a complete workflow of reservoir static modeling, from data loading to volumetric calculation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nickel Laterite Exploration and Exploitation as Metals Resources Optimization and Indonesian Industry Support</title>
      <link>//azizamir.github.io/publications/publication-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//azizamir.github.io/publications/publication-01/</guid>
      <description>Abstract This paper discusses the positive and negative impacts of the tectonic and topographical patterns in the Indonesian region. The negative impacts are earthquakes and other geological disasters, while the positive impact is the abundance of nickel laterite resources, which can be a natural asset for the country if managed properly. Indonesia has 8% of the world&amp;rsquo;s nickel reserves, making it one of the largest nickel producing countries. However, the low utilization of these resources and the unavailability of smelters in several nickel mining areas indicate the need for geoscientists to improve their understanding of nickel laterite and update their knowledge on efficient exploration techniques.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supervised Learning Implementation for Electrofacies, Lithofacies, and Depositional Environment Prediction using K-Nearest Neighbors Algorithm</title>
      <link>//azizamir.github.io/publications/publication-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//azizamir.github.io/publications/publication-02/</guid>
      <description>Abstract In this recent years, digitalization and automation have been massively transforming global industries to a new era of technology. This also applies in the petroleum industry by utilizing machine learning to aid exploration activities and analyze past data to extract the unseen data. This research implemented the usage of machine learning in petroleum geoscience by utilized the k-nearest neighbor (knn) as the supervised learning model algorithm to predict electrofacies pattern, lithofacies, and depositional environment classification using p-2 and k-1 well data as training dataset and b-1 well data as testing dataset where all the wells are on the same area.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
